Guide to the Department of Mathematics, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Mathematics, Yale University, records
1931-1973
RU 710
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.5
(11 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, personnel files, subject files, memoranda, and reports documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Department of Mathematics. Topics include administration and finance, curriculum planning, faculty appointments, personnel, fellowships, and admissions.
Yale University. Dept. of Mathematics
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic departments and programs of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See inventory for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, personnel files, subject files, memoranda, and reports documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Department of Mathematics. Topics include administration and finance, curriculum planning, faculty appointments, personnel, fellowships, and admissions.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by subject.
Mathematics -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Employees; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Dept. of Mathematics
- Records, 1931-1973; Accession 1974-A-001
  - Correspondence
    - 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Personnel files
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted until January 1, 2049
    - Auslander, Louis, 1954-1957 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Begle, E.E.: National Science Foundation Grant, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Curtis, Philip C.: proposal National Science Foundation, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Edwards, David A., 1957 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Ehresmann, Charles, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Feit, Walter, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Gerstenhaber, Murray, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Hochschild, G.P., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Kakutanf, Shizuo, 1948-1953 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Nunke, Ronald, 1854-1955 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Tamagawa, Tsuneo, 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Budget, 1948-1958
    - 1946-1949 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - 1949-1950 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - 1953-1954 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - 1955-1957 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Faculty: Acquiring Teachers, 1949-1959
    - 1949-1950 (Box 5, Folder 45 - 46)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 47 - 49)
    - 1950-1953 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - 1951-1952 (Box 6, Folder 51 - 53)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 6, Folder 54 - 55)
    - 1953-1954 (Box 6, Folder 56 - 58)
    - 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 59 - 60)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 62 - 63)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 64 - 65)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Appointments, Budgets, Correspondence, Reports, Work Sheets:
    - 1931-1936 (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - 1937-1938 (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 9, Folder 70)
    - 1939-1940 (Box 9, Folder 71)
    - 1940-1941 (Box 9, Folder 72)
    - 1941-1942 (Box 9, Folder 73)
    - 1942-1943 (Box 9, Folder 74)
    - 1943-1944 (Box 10, Folder 75)
    - 1944-1945 (Box 10, Folder 76)
  - Provost's office, 1946-1949 (Box 10, Folder 77)
  - Miscellaneous, 1948-1958 (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - Freshman Courses, 1949-1952 (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - Executive Committee: physical sciences, 1949-1953 (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - Science Majors at Yale, 1949-1953 (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - Graduate Courses, 1949-1955 (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Statistics, 1953-1956 (Box 11, Folder 83)
  - Graduate Fellowships, 1954-1955 (Box 11, Folder 84)
  - Contract: research on algebras, 1955-1957 (Box 11, Folder 85 - 86)
  - National Science Foundation, 1955-1957 (Box 11, Folder 87 - 88)
  - Executive Committee, 1956-1957 (Box 11, Folder 89)